## **Binit Kumar Jha**

Email: jhabinit4u@gmail.com Contact:+91-9911632440 Designation: Sr. Software Engineer

Role: Developer

## **Experience Summary:**

About 8 Years of extensive industry experience, current role as Senior Software Engineer, prior experience in leading development and production support teams.

Period Of Employment	Employer	Work Location	Position Duration Client Project
Aug, 2016 - Mar 2020	R Systems International Ltd	Noida, India	Sr Software Engineer   Aug 2016   Verimatrix   Projects: VOD Analytics
Feb,2015 - May,2016	Magna Infotech Ltd	Gurgaon, India	Software Engineer   Dec 2015 – May 2016   Bharti Infratel   Projects: Travel Requisition System
	Magna Infotech Ltd	Gurgaon, India	Software Engineer   Feb 2015 - Nov 2015   Bharti Infratel   Projects: Customer Portal
April,2013 - Feb,2015	Silicon web technology	Delhi,India	Software Developer   Apr 2013 - Feb 2015   Projects: ptutors.org
Dec-2011 - Mar-2013	Intaglio Softwares	Delhi,India	Software Engineer   Dec 2011 - Mar 2013   Projects: Sales Tracking

# **Qualifications**:

Education	Specialization	Institute/Board	Year of Passing	% Of Marks & Class/Grade Obtained
MCA. Computer Science & Engg.		Sathyabama University	May 2011	First class (8.1 CGPA)

## **Certifications:**

Certification	Date
<b>OCP-JP</b> (Oracle Certified Professional Java 6 Programmer)	2014

# **Technology Exposure:**

Programming Languages & Framework	Java, Spring(MVC,Core,Jdbc),Hibernate,SpringBoot,Restful-Webservices
Tools	Eclipse,Maven,SVN,GIT,GIT-Bash,Git-hub,winscp,putty,jenkins,jira
Servers	Apache Tomcat 8.0,IBM Websphere
Testing Tool	Junit
RDBMS Technologies	MySql, Oracle 11g
Operating systems	Windows,LINUX
Web Technologies	HTML, JSP,Servlet,JSON

### **Recent Achievements:**

Received Appreciation award for excellent contribution in the financial year 2018-2019 in R Systems.

#### **Industry Experience in Detail:**

Organization: R Systems International Ltd Aug 2016 - till date

**Project:** VOD Analytics

Customer: Verimatrix

Role: Developer

#### **Project Description:**

The VOD Analytics product consists of the following components. IDG(Interactive Data Gateway),OI(Operational intelligence), ReportOne .The IDG application is responsible for collecting data from operator sources at distributed geographic locations.Custom IDG(Interactive Data Gateway) Connectors have been built for several different VOD delivery platforms and back-offices,including Ericsson,Stream,Qam,SeaChange and many others.

### Responsibilities:

- To write server side business logic implementation and test cases
- Written java code to process and parsing the data from various sources and storing parsed data into oracle
- Involved in writing SQL and PL/SQL code to provide database functionality
- To communicate with testing team in order to resolve the testing bugs
- Performed regression testing using JUnit Testing Framework for the entire application
- To attend the daily stand-up meeting with client.
- Involved in Requirement gathering, Business Analysis and translated business requirements
- Collaborated with application teams to install operating system and Hadoop updates, version upgrades when required.

# Technologies and Tools used:

Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Jira, Git, Jenkins, Restful-webservices, Oracle, Gradle etc

### **Employer: Magna Infotech Ltd**

Project: Travel Requistion System Duration: Dec, 2015 - May 2016

Customer: Bharti Infratel

Role: Software Engineer

### Responsibilities

- To write server side business logic implementation and test cases
- Responsible for system development using Factory, DAO and MVC Design Patterns.
- Involved in writing SQL and PL/SQL code to provide database functionality
- Written java code for Module(International travel request) to process and storing data into oracle
- Involved in Requirement gathering, Business Analysis and translated business requirements
- Involved in implementation of the data access layer using Hibernate and Oracle.
- Performed regression testing using JUnit Testing Framework for the entire application

# Technologies and Tools used:

Java 7, Spring MVC, Hibernate 3, Maven 3, Rest Web Services, Oracle, IBMRAD, Maven, JQuery, JUnit,etc

Organization: Magna Infotech Ltd

Feb 2015 - Nov 2015

#### **Project: Customer Portal**

Customer: Bharti Infratel

Role: Software Engineer

## Responsibilities:

- To write server side business logic implementation and test cases
- Manage the lifecycle of the various Tower Types from raising SR to Deployment of Towers and Equipment's
- Track the status and location of each SR and Tower Types
- Manage end to end order fulfillment process that includes SR raise, approval process, reserve Sites
- Performed regression testing using JUnit Testing Framework for the entire application
- Proactively involved in grooming new team members.

## Technologies and Tools used:

Java, J2EE, EJB, JSP, JUnit, Servlets, Hibernate, Oracle, PL/SQL, TOAD, HTML, XML, JavaScript, ANT, JUnit, DB2 etc

Organization: Silicon Web Technology Apr 2013 - Feb 2015

Project: ptutors.org

Customer: Silicon Web Technology

Role: Software Developer

#### **Project Description:**

The Professional Tutors is a unique platforms which provides assistance and services to its members who are mainly students and tutors by helping them find suitable tutors or students depending on their requirement, residing at any plae around the globe.

#### Responsibilities:

- To write server side business logic implementation and test cases
- Responsible for system development using Factory, DAO and MVC Design Patterns.
- Written java code to process and storing data into oracle
- Involved in Requirement gathering, Business Analysis and translated business requirements
- Involved in implementation of the data access layer using Hibernate and MySQL.
- Performed regression testing using JUnit Testing Framework for the entire application
- Proactively involved in grooming new team members

### Technologies and Tools used:

Java 7, Spring MVC, JQuery, Hibernate, MySQL, JUnit, CSS, JSP etc

Organization: Intaglio Solutions	Dec 2011 – Mar 2013
•	

**Project:** Sales Tracking

Customer: Intaglio Softwares

Role: Software Developer

### Responsibilities:

- Design, and Implementation of ETL along with SQL\*Loader and PL/SQL.
- To write server side business logic implementation and test cases
- Responsible for system development using Factory, DAO and MVC Design Patterns.
- Written java code to process and storing data into oracle
- · Involved in Requirement gathering, Business Analysis and translated business requirements
- Involved in implementation of the data access layer using Hibernate and MySQL.
- Performed regression testing using JUnit Testing Framework for the entire application

## Technologies and Tools used:

Java 7, spring 3, Hibernate 3, Java Script, JQuery, JSP, HTML, CSS, Jasper Report, Junit, MySQL,etc

Personal Details:		
Father's Name	Father's Name Sushil Jha	
Marital Status	Married	
Nationality	Indian	
Languages	English, Hindi	
Personal Strength	Leadership skills, Self-confidence, Communication, Optimism and Hard working.	

### Declaration:

I hereby declare that the statements made above are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. Date:

Binit Kumar Jha

